Preliminary Inventory to the Lewis Henry Lapham Papers, 1971-1981
Hoover Institution Archives
Lewis Henry Lapham Papers
1971-1981
82023
Hoover Institution Archives
59 manuscript boxes (4.6 linear feet)
The collection contains correspondence, writings, and printed matter relating to Harper's Magazine and, specifically, to Lewis Henry Lapham's editorship of this publication. A significant amount of the correspondence pertains to submissions made to the magazine, including articles that were rejected. There are also some drafts and proofs of articles. Additional correspondence in the collection concerns work done for Harper's by associate editor, Nelson Aldrich, Jr., and by managing editor, David Sanford.
Lapham, Lewis H.
Access
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Chronology
1935 Born, San Francisco
1956 Awarded B.A. degree, Yale University
1956-1957 Attended Cambridge University
1957-1960 Reporter, San Francisco Examiner
1960-1962 Reporter, New York Herald Tribune
1971-1975 Managing editor, Harper's Magazine
1976-2006 Editor, Harper's Magazine
1988 Money and Class in America
1990 Imperial Masquerade
1997 Waiting for the Barbarians
2006 Pretensions to Empire: Notes on the Criminal Folly of the Bush Administration
2007 Founder, Lapham's Quarterly
Scope and Contents note
The collection contains correspondence, writings, and printed matter relating to Harper's Magazine and, specifically, to Lewis Henry Lapham's editorship of this publication. A significant amount of the correspondence pertains to submissions made to the magazine, including articles that were rejected. There are also some drafts and proofs of articles. Additional correspondence in the collection concerns work done for Harper's by associate editor, Nelson Aldrich, Jr., and by managing editor, David Sanford.
Harper's Magazine.; Journalism--United States.; Journalists.; United States--Civilization.; United States.
- Correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1971
  - 1972
    - A-F
    - G-K (Box 2)
    - L-O (Box 3)
    - P-V (Box 4)
    - W-Z (Box 5)
  - 1973
    - A-C
    - D-K (Box 6)
    - L-Q (Box 7)
    - R-Z (Box 8)
  - 1974
    - A
    - B-E (Box 9)
    - F-L (Box 10)
    - L-P (Box 11)
    - R-Z (Box 12)
- Nelson W. Aldrich, Jr. (associate editor, Harper's) correspondence) (Box 13)
  - 1974
    - A-L
    - M-Z (Box 14)
  - 1975
    - A-B
    - C-M (Box 15)
    - N-Z (Box 16)
- Correspondence (Box 17)
  - 1975
    - January-June
      - A-K
      - L-S (Box 18)
      - T-W (Box 19)
    - July-December
      - A-D
      - E-M (Box 20)
      - N-V (Box 21)
      - W-Z (Box 22)
  - 1976
    - January-June
      - A-E
      - F-M (Box 23)
      - M-S (Box 24)
      - T-W (Box 25)
    - July-December
      - A-D
      - E-M (Box 26)
      - M-V (Box 27)
      - W-Z (Box 28)
  - 1977
    - January-June
      - A-D
      - E-L (Box 29)
      - M-S (Box 30)
      - T-Z (Box 31)
    - July-December
      - A-C
      - C-K (Box 32)
      - L-Q (Box 33)
      - R-Z (Box 34)
- Rejections correspondence, 1977-1978
  - A
  - B-M (Box 35)
  - N-Z (Box 36)
- Correspondence
  - 1978
    - January-June
      - A-B
      - C-M (Box 37)
      - M-Z (Box 38)
    - July-December (Box 39)
      - A-F
      - G-M (Box 40)
      - N-W (Box 41)
      - X-Z (Box 42)
  - 1979
    - January-June
      - A-C
      - D-O (Box 43)
      - P-V (Box 44)
      - W-Z (Box 45)
    - July-December
      - A-C
      - D-J (Box 46)
      - K-O (Box 47)
      - P-S (Box 48)
      - T-Z (Box 49)
  - 1980
    - January-June
      - A-C
      - D-O (Box 50)
      - P-W (Box 51)
- David Sanford (managing editor, Harper's) correspondence, January-June 1980
  - A-F
  - G-Z (Box 52)
- Correspondence
  - 1980
    - July-December
      - A-D
      - E-O (Box 53)
      - P-Z (Box 54)
  - 1981
    - January-June
      - A-C
      - D-L (Box 55)
      - M-R (Box 56)
      - S-Z (Box 57)
- Miscellany
- Miscellany (Box 58-59)